Xinhu Li

CLVR Lab, Lira Lab Computer Science Department, USC

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My ultimate research goal is to develop robust and generalizable agents that learn how to solve tasks in unstructured environments. To achieve this goal, I am particularly interested in:

- Develop robust RL algorithms to boost generalization abilities across diverse tasks and environments.
- Developing autonomous RL algorithms that require minimal human oversight.

Key Fields: Robotics, Reinforcement Learning, Machine Learning, Decision Making

EDUCATION

University of Southern California, Viterbi School of Engineering M.S. in Artificial Intelligence, GPA: 3.81/4.00	Aug. 2020 - Dec. 2022
Zhejiang University of Technology B.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 3.73/5.00 (top 5%)	Sept. 2016 - Jun. 2020

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, Lira Lab, University of Southern California

Oct. 2023 - Present

https://xhlsgit.github.io

lixinhu98@gmail.com

Advisor: Prof. Erdem Biyik, Prof. Joseph J. Lim

[Target: ICML 2024] **Xinhu Li***, Ayush Jain*, Zhaojing Yang, Joseph J. Lim, Erdem Biyik. "Beyond Policy Transfer: Self-Supervised Reward Adaptation"

- Introduced self-supervised reward adaptation for adapting policies without human assistance.
- Outperforms all other adaptation methods in manipulation and locomotion experiments.

Research Assistant, CLVR Lab, University of Southern California May 2022 - Oct. 2023 Advisor: Prof. Joseph J. Lim

[Submitted to ICLR 2024] Ayush Jain*, Norio Kosaka*, Xinhu Li, Kyung-Min Kim, Joseph J. Lim. "Rethinking Actor-Critic: Successive Actors for Critic Maximization."

- Proposed a successive actor-critic structure for more effective action selection in actor-critic RL.
- Significantly improves the return in navigation, recommendation systems, and locomotion tasks.

Research Assistant, Institute of Digital Media Technology, ZJUT

Aug. 2019 - May 2020

Advisor: Prof. Meiyu Zhang

[Patent pending] Xinhu Li, Meiyu Zhang "Research and Implementation of Deep HDR Video Synthesis"

- Developed a custom LSTM for HDR video synthesis from footage with varying exposure times.
- Enhanced video quality substantially while remaining memory and compute-efficient.

Research Assistant, MoE Key Lab of Network and Software Security Assurance, Peking University

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Advisor: Prof. Zhong Chen

Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA) with bi-LSTM structure

• Introduced bi-LSTM for ABSA, enhancing precision in sentiment component extraction.

• Enables generalization through whole content, improving extraction accuracy.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Team Leader, ICPC Competition, Zhejiang University of Technology Jan. 2017 - Jan. 2020

Leadership Activities

Group Leader, Communication Club between Students and University Jan. 2016 - Jan. 2018

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Silver Award, China Collegiate Programming Contest, Final. (Rank 16)
- First Prize, Group Programming Ladder Tournament, China Collegiate Computing Contest
- Scholarship of Zhejiang Provincial Government (top 3%)
- Gold Award, The 2017 ACM-ICPC Asia Xi'an Regional Contest
- Silver Award, The 2017 ACM-ICPC Asia Shen Yang Regional Contest
- Gold Award, China Collegiate Programming Contest, GuiLin
- Silver Award, China Collegiate Programming Contest, JiLin

Teaching

Teaching Assistant, Database Systems, USC (Prof. Sathyanaraya Raghavachary)

Spring 2022

- Developed course homework and held weekly office hours (four hours/week) for student support.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

- Machine Learning/Robotics: ROS, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Matplotlib
- English Proficiency:
 - TOEFL: Reading 26, Listening 26, Speaking 24, Writing 24
 - GRE: Quantitative: 170, Verbal: 156, Analytical Writing 3.5
- Programming Language: Python, JAVA, C++/ C, C#, R, SQL
- Relevant Courses: Robotics, Machine Learning, Deep Reinforcement Learning, Computational Human Robot Interaction, Linear Algebra